Guide to the Autograph Files, 1669-1995
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Autograph Files
1669-1995
9.4 cubic feet (1 filing cabinet, 7 boxes, 3 framed items)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Letters, manuscripts, speeches, poems, and other items, primarily resulting from an official connection with Vassar College, written by Vassar students, faculty or staff, or by persons of historical and cultural significance.
Scope and Content Note
Letters with some manuscripts, speeches, poems, and other items, primarily resulting from an official connection with Vassar College, written by Vassar students, faculty or staff, or by persons of historical and cultural significance.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Separated Material
Many items in the Autograph Files were separated from other collections.
The letters of many individuals were separated from the collection and added to the Mitchell Kennerley Papers, June 1984. These include letters from Randolph G. Adams, Arnold Bennet, John Carter, Arthur Davison Ficke, Frank Harris, Allan A. Jefferson, Peter McArthur, and Blanche Shoemaker Wagstaff.
The letters of Margaret Stanton Lawrence and Martha C. Wright were separated from the collection and added to the Elizabeth Cady Stanton Papers.
The letters of Eva March Tappan were separated from the collection and added to the Eva March Tappan Papers.
The letters of Marianne C. Moore and Mary W. Moore were separated from the collection and added to the Marianne Moore Papers, Dec 2022.
The letters of Amy Lowell were separated from the collection and added to the Amy Lowell Papers, Jan 2023.
Letters to Vassar College President Sarah Blanding from various individuals were separated from the collection and returned to the Vassar College Office of the President Records - Sarah Gibson Blanding Files, Feb 2025. Correspondents include: Marian Anderson, Elizabeth Bowen, Dorothy Canfield Fisher, J. Robert Oppenheimer, Eleanor Roosevelt, and Adlai E. Stevenson.
The letters of Edward Elsworth were separated from the collection and added to the Edward Elsworth Papers, Jan 2026.
The letters of Margaret Lewis Livingston (1783-1860) were separated from the collection and added to the Margaret Lewis Livingston Papers, Feb 2026.
The letters of Henrietta Gardner Macy (VC Spec 1886-1887) were separated from the collection and added to the Henrietta Macy Papers, Feb 2026.
Subject Headings
Names:
James Family; Roosevelt Family
Organizations:
Vassar College--Students; Vassar College--Faculty; Vassar College--Employees; Vassar College. Department of History; Vassar College. Library; Vassar College. Observatory; Association of Collegiate Alumnae (U.S.); Bryn Mawr College; Spellman College; Yale University
Subjects:
Equal rights amendments; Feminism; Feminists; Women--Education; Women--Employment; Women missionaries--India; Women's health services; Women--Social conditions; Women's rights; Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women's colleges--Pennsylvania--Bryn Mawr; Women authors, American; Women artists; Wages and women; Women in politics; Women social reformers; Missions--India; Syphilis; Ovariotomy; Peace treaties; Presidents--United States--Election; Slavery--Anti-slavery movements; Abolitionists--New York (State)--Rochester; Social work with African Americans; Fugitive slaves--New York (State)--Rochester; Fugitive slaves--Kentucky; Shoemakers--Massachusetts--Woburn; Apprentices--Massachusetts--Woburn; Strikes and lockouts--Marble industry and trade--Vermont; Nonviolence--Religious aspects; Shakers; Christianity; Chastity; Authors, English; Authors, American; Poetry; Publishers and publishing; Screenwriters--California--Hollywood; Fires--Massachusetts--Salem; Educational fund raising; Dogs; Revolutions--Europe; Law students; Theater--Spain; Music--Study and teaching; Peasantry--Russia; Patriotism
Places:
New York (N.Y.)--Social life and customs; New York (N.Y.)--Politics and government; Woburn (Mass.)--Economic conditions; Boston (Mass.)--Social life and customs; Boston (Mass.)--Religious life and customs; United States--Politics and government; United States--Social life and customs; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; United States--Foreign relations--France; France--Foreign relations--United States; Europe--Politics and government; Europe--History--1848-1849; Scotland--Social conditions; Ghana--Description and travel
Document Types:
Autographs; Correspondence; Poems
VCL Categories:
Autographs; Vassar College; Women's History
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, Apr 2008.
Updated by Gretchen Maslin and Jenna Effenberger, 2011-2012.
Updated by Mark Seidl, Dec 2019.
Updated by Emma Gronbeck, Feb 2023 - Feb 2026.
Acquisition Information
An artificial collection, collected over several decades by Vassar College Library staff. Some materials were separated from other collections and added to the Autograph Files.
Many letters were the gift of Ruth Fitch Mason (VC 1912).
Series List
  A — B — C — D — E — F — G — H — I — J — K — L — M —
  N — O — P — Q — R — S — T — U — V — W — X-Y-Z
  Miscellaneous Autograph Books
Container List
- A
  - Abbott, Francis Matilda, 1907 Nov 25; (1 letter)
  - Abbott, Lyman, 1878-1916, undated; (1 autograph, 7 letters)
  - Abbott, Mary M., 1903 Aug 19; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Aberdeen and Temair, Ishbel Maria (Marjoribanks) Gordon, Marchioness of, undated; (1 card)
  - Acheson, Dean, 1950-1968; (4 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Adam, Adolph Charles, undated; (3 letters)
  - Adamic, Louis, 1934 Nov 16, undated; (2 letters)
  - Adams, Charles Francis, 1908 Jun 27; (1 letter)
  - Adams, Elizabeth K., 1913 Aug 11; (1 letter)
  - Adams, George Burton, 1903 May 20; (1 letter)
  - Adams, John, undated; (2 letters)
  - Adams, John Quincy, 1783
    — Includes material on Paris peace treaty and national politics.
  - Adams, John Quincy, 1825, 1834; (1 letter facsimile, 1 photocopied letter) (Box 1)
  - Adams, Leonie, 1872 Apr 23; (2 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Adams, R.F.D., undated; (1 letter)
  - Adams, Ruth, 1921 Jun; (1 letter)
  - Adams, Rev. William, 1875 Feb 4; (1 letter)
  - Addams, Jane, 1897-1934; (8 letters)
  - Aeolian Co., 1929 Jun 22-Oct 24; (3 letters)
  - Agassiz, Elizabeth C., undated; (1 letter)
  - Alcott, Amos Bronson, 1881 Oct 14; (1 letter)
  - Alcott, Louisa May, 1875, 1889; (1 letter, 1 frontispiece)
  - Aldrich, Alexander, 1968 May 8; (1 letter)
  - Aldrich, Richard, 1925-1931, undated; (5 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Allen, Agnes Rodgers, 1940; (4 letters)
  - Allen, Florence E., 1955 May 9; (1 letter)
  - Allen, Fredrick Lewis, 1924 May 29; (1 letter)
  - Allen, Hewey, 1926 Nov 20; (2 letters)
  - Allen, Low, undated; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Allen, Walter, 1982 Sep 7; (1 letter)
  - Andersen, Hans Christian, 1850; (1 letter)
  - Anderson, Florence (Bennett), 1939; (2 letters, 1 manuscript)
  - Anderson, Martin B., 1875 Feb 1; (1 letter)
  - Anderson, Sherwood, undated; (1 letter)
  - Angell, Gertrude, 1945 Mar 1; (1 letter)
  - Angell, James B., 1875-1890; (2 letters)
  - Apthorp, William F., 1897 May 18; (1 letter)
  - Armstrong, S.C., 1875 Feb 8; (1 letter)
  - Armstrong, Sarah F. (Sheppard), 1909 Oct 24; (2 letters, 2 envelopes)
  - Arne, Sigrid, 1945 Jul 28; (1 letter)
  - Arnim, Elizabeth, undated; (1 letter)
  - Arnold, Matthew, 1884-1893; (2 letters)
  - Arthur, Jean, undated; (1 letter)
  - Ashley, Fredrick William, 1936, undated; (1 invitation, 2 letters, 1 poem)
  - Assatouroff, Jenny ber, 1899; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Astor, John Jacob, undated; (1 letter)
  - Austen, John, undated; (1 letter)
  - Avery, Alida Cornelia, 1905-1907, undated; (3 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Avery, Mary L., 1844 Aug 2; (1 letter)
  - Avery, Myrz H., 1932; (1 letter)
  - Axon, William E.A., 1877 Jan 27; (1 letter)
- B
  - [B., L.J.] to Lucy Maynard Salmon, 1900 Nov 22; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - "Bab,", 1942, undated; (2 letters)
  - Bacheller, Ann, undated; (1 letter)
  - Bacheller, Irving, undated; (1 letter)
  - Backus, Truman J., 1875-1895; (8 letters, 2 envelopes)
  - Bacon, Dr. Leonard W., [Missing as of Feb 2023]
  - Baird, Prof. Spencer, 1875 Feb 3; (1 letter)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard, 1926 Jan 9; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Baker, S. Josephine, 1917 Oct 11; (1 letter)
  - Baldridge, Letitia, 1961 Jun 19; (1 letter)
  - Baldwin, Simon, 1917; (2 letters)
  - Bales, Robert H., 1953 Oct 15; (1 letter)
  - Ball, George W., 1968 Jul 5; (1 letter)
  - Ballou, Esther, 1964; (2 letters)
  - Bancroft, George, 1880-1881; (2 letters)
  - Banfield, Edith C., 1890 Feb 7; (1 letter)
  - Bangs, John Kendrick, 1901-1918; (2 letters)
  - Banks, Isabella, 1887 Sep 27; (1 letter)
  - Banning, Margaret Culkin, 1937 May 15; (1 letter)
  - Bannister, Zilpah Polly, 1866 Jan 15; (1 letter, 3 copies)
  - Barbour, Clarence A., 1920 Jul 24; (1 letter)
  - Barker, Granville, 1943 May 5; (1 letter)
  - Barlow, George S., 1820 Oct 24; (1 letter)
  - Barlow, Howard, 1965 Dec 9; (1 letter)
  - Barlow, Jane, 1913 Dec 31; (1 letter)
  - Barnard, F.C., 1891 May 20; (1 letter)
  - Barnard, Fredrick Augustus Porter, 1864 Apr 15; (1 letter)
  - Barnard, George, 1845-1942; (5 letters)
  - Barnes, Albert, 1860 May 17; (1 letter)
  - Barney, Mary (Case), undated; (1 letter)
  - Barrie, James M., 1891 Apr 16; (1 letter)
  - Barry, Carola E., 1963 Sep 18; (1 letter)
  - Barton, Clara, 1892 Mar 21; (1 letter)
  - Baruch, Bernard, 1945 May 23; (1 letter)
  - Barus, Annie (Howes), 1926 Feb 11; (1 letter, 1 manuscript)
  - Bascom, Prof. John, undated; (1 letter)
  - Baskin, Leonard, 1988 Mar 27; (1 manuscript)
  - Bates, Katherine Lee, 1898 Mar 16; (1 letter)
  - Bates, Sarah Glazier, 1869-1879; (3 letters)
  - Bauer, Harold, 1909 Mar 22; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Baxter, James, 1937 Nov 26; (1 letter)
  - Baxter, John B.M., 1944 Mar 8; (1 letter)
  - Baxter, Percival, 1920 Dec 20; (1 postcard, 1 envelope)
  - Bayh, Birch, 1970 Sep 11; (1 letter)
  - Baylinson, A.S., 1940; (2 letters)
  - Bazzini, Antonio, 1843 Sep 14; (1 letter)
  - Beach, Lillian T., 1895 May 30; (1 letter)
  - Beard, D. C., undated; (1 card)
  - Beecher, Catherine E., to John H. Raymond, 1872 May 22; (1 letter)
  - Beecher, Henry Ward, undated; (1 letter)
  - Belbenoit, Rene, undated; (1 letter)
  - Bell, Francis L., 1939 May 3, undated; (3 letters)
  - Bellerman, Dr. Heinrich, 1897 Apr 16; (1 letter)
  - Bellows, Henry, 1875 Feb 5; (1 letter)
  - Belmont, Eleanor R., 1917 Apr 9; (1 letter)
  - Benes, Eduard, 1924 Feb-Apr; (2 letters)
  - Benét, William Rose, 1931-1936, undated; (3 letters)
  - Benjamin, Walter R., 1908 Oct 24; (1 letter)
  - Bennett, Arnold, 1913-1926; (2 letters)
  - Bennett, Paul A., 1957 Apr 10; (1 letter)
  - Benson, Arthur C., 1913 Dec 23; (1 letter)
  - Benson, E.F., 1913 Dec 31; (1 letter)
  - Benton, Joel, 1899 May 29; (1 letter)
  - Benton, William, 1956 Dec; (2 letters, 1 news article)
  - Berle, Adolph A., Jr., 1938 Aug 30; (1 letter)
  - Berlioz, Hector, undated; (1 letter)
  - Bernard, Mary Lawrence, 1920 Feb 19; (1 letter)
  - Berry, Kate, 1875; (1 postcard, 2 letters, 1 envelope with 3 assorted items including photograph)
  - Berry, Martha, 1932 Nov 11; (1 letter)
  - Berton, Henri-Montan, 1839 Nov 11; (1 letter)
  - Besant, Walter, 1895-1897; (2 letters)
  - Beukema, Herman, 1945 Jul 2; (2 letters)
  - Bianchi, John, 1918 Jul 30; (1 letter)
  - Biddle, George, 1940 Oct 28; (1 letter)
  - Bigelow, Poultney, undated; (2 letters)
  - Billings, Henry, 1940 Nov 22; (1 letter)
  - Bingham, Hiram, 1916 Oct 6; (1 letter)
  - Bingham, Millicent Todd, 1935 Jul 28; (1 letter)
  - Bishop, Harriette (Warner) (VC 1867), 1867-1943; (22 letters, 6 envelopes)
    — Includes letters to Helen Kenyon, Maria Mitchell, "Nellie" Raymond, and Adelaide Underhill.
  - Bishop, Helen, 1944 May 29; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Bishop, Mabel, 1940 Oct 21; (1 letter)
  - Bizet, Georges, undated; (2 letters)
  - Black, Ebenezer Charlton, 1898 Jan 4; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Black, Hugh, 1915 May 26; (1 letter)
  - Blackwell, Alice Stone, 1896-1935; (4 letters)
  - Blackwell, Antoinette Louisa Brown, [Missing as of April 2008]
  - Blackwell, Elizabeth, 1960; (2 letters)
  - Blackwell, Dr. Emily, 1896
    — Includes material on excessive practice of ovariotomy and dangers to women from syphilitic husbands.
  - Blaikie, William, 1882 May 4; (1 letter)
  - Blake, Dr. Mary J. Stafford, 1875 Apr 4; (1 letter)
  - Blake, Sillie Devereaux, 1875-1894; (4 letters)
  - Blashfield, Edwin Howland, 1915-1916; (3 letters)
  - Blatch, Harriet Stanton, undated; (2 letters)
  - Bliss, Rev. George R., 1875 Feb 19; (1 letter)
  - Bliss, H.S., 1919 May 16; (1 letter)
  - Bliven, Bruce, 1932 Nov 9; (1 letter)
  - Bloomer, Amelia, 1852 Dec 24; (1 letter)
  - Blunt, Katherine, 1913 Aug 25; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Boieldieu, Francois Adrien, undated; (1 letter)
  - Bois, Jules, undated; (1 letter, 1 manuscript)
  - Boissevain, Eugen, undated; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Bolton, Sarah Knowles, 1895 Mar 25; (1 letter)
  - Bond, Elizabeth Powell, 1914 Jun 9; (1 letter)
  - Bondeau, 1936-1964, undated; (4 letters)
  - Booth, George, 1956 May 27; (1 letter)
  - Booth, Lydia, 1844, 1847, 1912; (4 letters)
    — Includes 2 letters from Frances Swan about Lydia Booth.
  - Booth, Mary L., undated; (1 letter)
  - Booth, William, 1895 Feb 22; (1 card)
  - Borchard, Edwin M., 1938 Oct 14; (1 letter)
  - Borden, Fanny, 1942 Feb 7; (1 letter)
  - Borg, Selma, undated; (1 letter)
  - Borowy, W., 1924 Oct 13; (1 letter)
  - Bosanquest, Ester Cleveland, undated; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Boscom, John, undated; (1 letter)
  - Bossi, M. Enrico, 1897 May 1; (1 letter)
  - Boulanger, Nadia, 1937 Apr 25; (1 letter)
  - Bowditch, Nathaniel, 1806 Sep; (3 letters)
  - Bowen, Elizabeth, 1952; (1 letter)
  - Bowen, Francis, 1850 Aug 15; (1 letter)
  - Bowles, Chester, 1958 Nov 25; (1 letter)
  - Bowman, E.M., 1995 Mar 28; (1 letter)
  - Boyd, James, 1930; (2 letters, 2 envelopes)
  - Boyd, Ruth, 1912-1936, undated; (5 letters, 1 manuscript)
  - Boyd, Thomas, 1918-1934
    — Includes material on work as screen writer in Hollywood (1931), being a father, World War I experiences, and other issues.
  - Boyd-Carpenter, William, 1921 Feb 12; (1 letter, 1 manuscript)
  - Boynton, Marjorie M., 1939 Nov 17; (1 letter)
  - Brahms, Johannes, undated; (2 letters, 1 translation)
  - Braislin, Priscilla H. (VC Faculty), 1883 Feb 28; (1 letter)
  - Brant, Henry, 1963 Sep 23; (2 letters)
  - Breckenridge, Henry, 1922 Oct 5; (1 letter)
  - Brent, Charles Henry, 1904-1926; (4 letters)
  - Bretz, J. P., undated; (1 letter)
  - Brewster, Benjamin H., 1883 Jan 22; (1 letter)
  - Bridges, Robert, undated; (1 card)
  - Bright, Jacob, 1870 Sep 26; (1 letter)
  - Bright, John, 1858-1882; (3 letters)
  - Brinnin, John Malcolm, 1946 Apr 20; (1 letter)
  - Brinton, Crane, 1951 Oct 2; (1 letter)
  - Brittain, Vera, 1936 Dec 2; (1 letter)
  - Brittan, Mary Burta, 1937-1938; (2 letters)
  - Brogan, Denis, 1963 Dec 15; (1 letter)
  - Bromfield, Alfred J., 1885 Jan 19; (1 letter)
  - Brooks, John S., 1904 Jan 17, undated; (1 envelope, 2 letters)
  - Brooks, Noah, undated; (1 letter)
  - Brooks, Phillips, 1843-1891; (2 envelopes, 11 letters)
  - Browgham, H.B., 1916 Aug-Nov; (2 letters)
  - Brown, E. Melville, 1937 Mar 24; (1 letter)
  - Brown, Ford, undated; (1 letter)
  - Brown, Helen D., 1934 Mar 18, undated; (2 letters)
  - Brown, Henry, undated; (1 letter)
  - Brown, Zenith, undated; (3 letters)
  - Browne, F. Maurice, 1908 Aug 28; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Brownell, Lucy E., 1876 Mar 6; (1 letter)
  - Brownlow, W.G., 1863 Dec 16; (1 letter)
  - Bruce, Edward, 1940 Oct; (2 letters)
  - Bruce, James M., 1897-1900; (3 letters)
  - Bruch, Max, 1867 Apr 27; (1 letter)
  - Bruhl, L. Levy, 1919 Sep 28; (1 letter)
  - Bryan, E.B., 1917 Mar 27; (1 letter)
  - Bryant, William Cullen, 1870 Jun 10; (1 letter)
  - Bryce, James, 1896 Feb 27; (1 letter, 1 envelope) (Box 1)
  - Buchan, Anna O. Douglas, undated; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Buchanan, James, undated; (1 envelope)
  - Buchwald, Art, 1977 Jul-Sep; (5 letters)
  - Buck, Gertrude, 1909-1915; (2 letters)
  - Buck, Pearl S., 1938-1967
    — Includes correspondence with Alma Lutz on equal rights amendment and Buck's writing and speaking work.
  - Buckingham, Stephen, 1878-1885, undated; (10 letters, 2 envelopes)
    — Includes correspondence between Benson J. Lossing and Stephen Buckingham on women as trustees.
  - Buckmaster, Henrietta, undated; (2 letters)
  - Bunche Ralphe J., 1953-1964, undated; (2 letters, 1 quotation)
  - Bundy, McGeorge, 1955-1962; (2 letters)
  - Burne-Jones, Edward, 1895-1931, undated; (2 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Burnett, Frances Hodgson, 1885 Sep; (autograph)
  - Burns, John, 1955-1962; (2 letters)
  - Burns, Robert, 1840; (1 facsimile)
  - Burnside, Helen W., 1873 Sep 22; (1 letter)
  - Burton, W.L., 1915 Apr 26; (1 letter)
  - Butler, Josephine E., 1871 Feb 21; (1 letter, 1 copy)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murry, 1896 Mar 4; (4 letters, 1 article, 1 invitation)
  - Butler, R.A., 1944 May; (2 letters)
  - Bynner, Witter, 1912-1913; (4 letters, 2 envelopes)
  - Byron, George Gordon Noel, 1823; (1 letter)
- C
  - Cable, George Washington, 1881 Mar 26; (1 letter)
  - Cadman, S. Parkes (Samuel Parkes), 1916-1926; (2 letters)
  - Caine, Hall, 1909 Sep 21; (1 letter)
  - Caldwell, Samuel L. (1820-1889), 1882-1967, undated; (16 letters, 2 envelopes, 1 invitation)
  - Caldwell, Samuel L., M.D (1853-1942), 1880-1939, undated; (14 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Calhoun, John C., 1824-1926; (4 letters)
  - Calthorpe, undated; (1 letter)
  - Calverton, V.F., 1928 Aug 23; (1 letter)
  - Cameron, Edward M., Jr., 1950 Sep 25; (1 letter)
  - Campbell, George D., 1923 May 1; (1 letter)
  - Campbell, Helen, 1981-1986; (2 letters)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1931-1945; (17 letters, 6 envelopes)
  - Carden, Mae, 1919 Jul 30, undated; (1 letter, 3 postcards)
  - Carlyle, Thomas, 1932-1934, undated; (2 letters, 1 news clipping)
  - Carnegie, Andrew, undated; (1 signature)
  - Carney, Albert J., undated; (1 letter)
  - Carson, Gerald, 1954-1964; (1 letter, 1 postcard)
  - Carter, Edna, 1956 Aug 27, undated; (2 letters)
  - Cary, Alice, 1863-1870; (4 letters)
  - Cary, Lillian, undated; (1 letter)
  - Cary, Melbert Brinckerhoff Jr., 1934 Aug 13; (1 postcard)
  - Cary, Phoebe, undated; (2 letters)
  - Case, Clifford P., 1957 Feb; (2 letters)
  - Castle, W.D., 1931 Oct 7; (1 letter)
  - Cather, Willa, 1935 Aug 29, undated; (2 letters, 1 card)
  - Catt, Carrie Chapman, 1945 May; (3 letters)
  - Cattell, James McKeen, 1906 May 5; (1 letter)
  - Catternall, Ralph C.W., 1906 Nov 13; (1 letter)
  - Ceely, Robert, 1986 Jun; (2 letters)
  - Chadbourne, Paul Ansel, undated; (1 letter)
  - Chadwick, George Whitefield, 1897 May 22; (1 letter)
  - Champney, Elizabeth (Williams) (VC 1869), 1865-1940; (10 letters, 1 postcard, 1 manuscript draft)
  - Chapin, E.H., 1869 Jan 26; (1 letter)
  - Chapin, Mary Whitney, 1884-1895; (3 letters)
  - Chapman, John Jay, 1923 Mar 30, undated; (1 letter, 2 signatures)
  - Chapman, R.W., 1908 Jun 29; (1 letter)
  - Charpentier, Gustave, 1933 Aug 11; (1 letter)
  - Chatterton, Thomas, undated; (1 manuscript)
  - Child, Francis James, 1881 Feb 5; (1 note)
  - Childs, Mary Cole, undated; (1 note)
  - Chittenden, Kate S., 1932-1946; (2 letters)
  - Choate, Augusta, 1913 Aug 26; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Choate, Joseph, 1890-1917; (2 letters)
  - Christie, Dorothy, undated; (5 letters)
  - Churchill, Winston, 1940 Apr 20; (1 autographed photo)
  - Ciechanowski, J., 1928 May 31; (1 letter)
  - Clark, Charles Upson, 1918 Jul 20; (1 letter, 1 envelope, 1 newspaper clipping)
  - Clark, E.M., undated; (1 postcard)
  - Clark, Eleanor, 1984-1985; (2 letters, 2 envelopes)
  - Clark, Kate (Upson), undated; (1 signature)
  - Clark, Mary Vida, 1913 Jul 28; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Clark, Samuel, 1889 Jul 13; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Clark, Thomas March, 1875-1890; (5 letters)
  - Clarke, Edward H., 1875 Feb 6; (2 letters)
  - Clarke, Sarah Freeman, 1887 Sep 29; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Claudel, Paul, 1927 Mar 16; (1 letter, 1 photo)
  - Clemens, Charles Edwin, 2009 Apr 24; (1 letter)
  - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1881-1901, undated; (6 letters, 1 envelope, 1 card)
  - Cleveland, Frances F., undated; (1 letter)
  - Cloetta, M, 1915 Jun 15; (1 letter)
  - Clough, Anne Jemima, 1888 Jun 8, undated; (5 letters)
  - Clough, Blanche Athena, 1897 Dec 27; (1 letter)
  - Clulow, H.V., 1923 Dec 28; (1 letter)
  - Cobb, Dorothy Penrose, 1915 Oct 17; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Coes, Mary, 1898 Jan 18; (1 letter)
  - Coffin, A.H., 1867 Jul 3; (1 letter)
  - Coffin, Elizabeth R., 1917-1931; (5 letters)
  - Coffin, Tristram, 1915-1951; (4 letters, 1 newspaper clipping)
  - Colby, Emma M., undated; (1 letter)
  - Cole, Rossetter Gleason, 1910 Sep 29; (1 letter)
  - Cole, Timothy, 1916 Dec 24; (1 letter)
  - Coleridge, Samuel Taylor, 1818 Oct 2; (1 letter with 2 transcripts)
  - Collyer, Robert, undated; (1 letter)
  - Colum, Padraic, 1931 Jul 24; (1 letter, 1 review
  - Commons, John R., 1932 Jan 5; (1 letter)
  - Combe, Harvey, 1827 Feb 28; (1 letter)
  - Comstock, Ada, 1917, 1937; (2 letters)
  - Conrad, Joseph, 1904-1924; (4 letters, 2 envelopes)
  - Conreid, Heinrich, 1903 Feb 17; (1 letter)
  - Conron, Georgianna, 1916 May 18; (1 letter)
  - Conrow, Wilfred S., 1931 May; (2 letters)
  - Converse & Co. Publishers, 1885 May 11; (1 letter)
  - Conway, Moncure D., 1875-1902; (2 letters)
  - Cook, Joseph, 1879 Mar 5; (1 letter)
  - Cooke, A, 1901 Jun 17; (1 letter)
  - Cooke, Rose Terry, 1881 Aug 18; (1 letter)
  - Coolidge, Archibald Cary, 1916 Sep 19; (1 letter)
  - Coonley, Queenie (Ferry), 1936 Oct 16; (1 letter)
  - Cooper, Peter, 1875 Feb 8; (1 letter)
  - Copland, Aaron, 1945 Oct; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Copland, Suzanne, 1938-1939; (5 letters)
  - Cornell, Antoinette, undated; (1 envelope, 1 letter)
  - Cornell, Francis, undated; (1 letter)
  - Cornwell, Louise, undated; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Corr, Maureen, 1962-1963; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Corson, Hiram, 1887 Apr 22; (1 letter)
  - Cortissoz, Royal, 1921 Oct 26; (1 letter)
  - Cotta, Alix von, 1886 Dec 22; (1 letter)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1969 Apr 9; (1 letter)
  - Cowles, Rev. A.W., 1864-1869; (3 letters)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, 1933 Dec 8; (1 letter)
  - Coxe, Arthur Cleveland, 1879 Dec 22; (1 letter)
  - Coykendall, Samuel D., 1895 Jun 19; (1 letter)
  - Cracraft, Tom Adrian, undated; (4 fragments, 1 envelope)
  - Crawford, Francis Marion, 1898 Jan 17; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Cretin, Eunice M., 1872 Nov 15; (1 letter)
  - Crookshank, Emma (Comfort), 1949-1987, undated; (5 letters, 3 envelopes, 1 newspaper clipping)
  - Crookshank, Harry, 1944-1958; (9 letters, 4 envelopes, 1 newspaper clipping)
  - Crosby, Howard, undated; (1 letter)
  - Crowell, E.P., 1887 Sep 21; (1 letter)
  - Curie, Marie, 1921-1982; (5 letters, 1 envelope, 1 monograph)
  - Currier, Isabel, 1947-1961; (2 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Curry, J.L.M., 1870; (1 letter)
  - Curtis, George Ticknor, undated; (1 poem)
  - Curtis, George William, 1863-1891, undated; (23 letters, 6 envelopes)
  - Curtis, Mrs. George William, undated; (1 letter)
  - Cushing, Florence M. (VC 1874), undated; (13 letters, 2 envelopes)
  - Cushman, Charlotte, 1871 Jul 15; (1 letter)
  - Custer, Elizabeth (Bacon), undated; (3 letters, 1 envelope)
  - Cutlor, Sen. Leslie B., 1949; (2 letters)
  - Cuyler, Theodore L., 1875 Jan 15; (1 letter)
- D
  - Daggett, Susan E., 1877; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Dalzell, N.R., 1919 Dec 14; (1 letter)
  - Dame, Maria, 1889 Oct 3; (1 letter, 1 envelope)
  - Damer, Anne Seymour, 1826 Jul 24; (1 letter)
  - Damer, Anne Seymour, 1826 Jul 31; (1 photocopied will) (Box 1)